Finding Aid for William G. Milliken papers 1961-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Administrative / Executive Files
  - Staff Files, 224 linear feet
    - Linda Slotsema 1977-1982
      - Governors' Associations
        - National Governors' Association
          - Meetings
            - 1981 Summer, August 9-11, 4 folders (Box 807)
            - 1982 Winter, February 21-23, 4 folders (Box 807)
            - 1982 Summer, August 8-10, 4 folders (Box 807)
              (includes Executive Committee Meetings)
          - Topical Files
            - Awards Programs 1980-1982, 4 folders (Box 807)
            - Bulletins (Box 807)
            - By-Laws (Box 807)
            - Center for Policy Research (Box 807)
            - Correspondence 1980-1982, 2 folders (Box 807)
            - Directory of Staff Assistants 1980-1981 (Box 807)
            - Education Position (Box 807)
            - "Eliminating Roadblocks to Efficient State Government," 1981 (Box 807)
            - Faxpak Telecommunications 1980-1981 (Box 807)
            - Federalism Initiatives 1980-1981 (Box 807)
            - Grants-In-Aid Priorities (Box 807)
            - Info Letter 1981 (Box 807)
            - International Transportation Exchange, Center for 1980 (Box 807)
            - Legislative Summary 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 807)
            - Local Financial Management 1980 (Box 807)
            - News Releases (Box 807)
            - Policy Initiatives, State 1980 (Box 807)
            - Proposal for Organizational Change 1980 (Box 807)
            - Rehabilitation 1979-1980 (Box 807)
            - Restoring Balance to the Federal System (Box 807)
            - Revenue Sharing 1979-1980 (Box 807)
            - Transition Documents 1982 (Box 807)
            - Urban Water Systems 1980 (Box 807)
            - Welfare Reform 1981 (Box 807)
        - Republican Governors' Association (Box 808)
          - Annual Conferences
            - Austin November 1979 (Box 808)
            - New Orleans November 1981 (Box 808)
          - Communications Notebook 1982 (Box 808)
          - Policy Positions Adopted/Proposed (Box 808)
          - Successful Programs Implemented in Michigan (Box 808)
      - Milliken's Stand on National Issues
        - December 28, 1978-August 22, 1981 (7 folders, Summary/Index listed chronologically) (Box 808)
        - July 21, 1981-June 10, 1982 (2 folders, Index at front of file) (Box 808)
      - Topical Files
        - A-95 Review System (Box 808)
        - Administrative Hearings, Centralization of 1979-1980 (Box 808)
        - Amtrak 1979-1980 (Box 808)
        - Amway Railroad (Box 808)
        - Anti-trust Suit (Cereal cos./FTC) 1978-1979 (Box 808)
        - Arbitration, Compulsory 1979 (Box 808)
        - Audit Reports 1975-1979 (Box 808)
        - Auto Industry Summit 1980-1982, 5 folders (Box 808)
        - Balance of Trade (Box 809)
        - Bay County Fiscal Situation 1979-1980 (Box 809)
        - Benton Harbor 1980 (Box 809)
        - Block Grants 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 809)
        - Block, John (visit to Michigan) (Box 809)
        - Boundary Commission 1978 (Box 809)
        - Budgets (UP, Washington Offices) 1979-1980 (Box 809)
        - Buy A Car (BAC America) 1980 (Box 809)
        - Cabinet 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 809)
        - Canada/US Relations 1978-1981, 3 folders (Box 809)
        - Capital Recovery Act (Box 809)
        - Caribbean/Central American Action 1980-1982, 3 folders (Box 809)
        - Cass County 1979-1980 (Box 809)
        - Census 1980 (Box 809)
        - Chatham Project 1980 (Box 809)
        - Chrysler Corporation 1979-1980 (Box 809)
        - Cities in Transition 1977 (Box 809)
        - Clean Air Act 1979-1982 (Box 809)
        - Community Correctional Facilities 1979-1980 (Box 809)
        - Community Development 1980, 3 folders (Box 809)
        - Community Development Cabinet 1979-1980
          - General 1980 (Box 809)
          - Budget 1980 (Box 809)
          - Correspondence 1979-1980 (Box 809)
          - Meetings 1979-1980, 8 folders (Box 809)
          - Message 1979 (Box 809)
          - Publications (Box 809)
          - Reports 1980 (Box 809)
          - Staffing/Work Plan 1979, 2 folders (Box 809)
        - Community Services (Department of Labor) 1978-1980 (Box 809)
        - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (CETA) 1978-1981, 2 folders (Box 809)
        - Congressional (Box 810)
          - Delegation Briefings 1979-1981, 6 folders (Box 810)
          - Records (Michigan Delegation) 1981-1982 (Box 810)
        - Council for Project Development, 3 folders (Box 810)
        - Countercyclical Fiscal Assistance 1979-1980 (Box 810)
        - Criminal Justice Program 1980 (Box 810)
        - Cuban/Haitian Resettlement 1980-1982 (Box 810)
        - Defense Spending, Regional Impact 1980-1981 (Box 810)
        - Detroit
          - Economic Development Corporation 1980 (Box 810)
          - General Hospital 1979 (Box 810)
          - Light Rail/Subway 1980 (Box 810)
          - Office (Correspondence) 1979-1980 (Box 810)
          - Riverfront conference 1980 (Box 810)
        - Disability Insurance 1980-1981 (Box 810)
        - Distressed Cities 1980 (Box 810)
        - Economic Program for the 80s (Jimmy Carter) (Box 810)
        - Education Commission of the States 1979-1980 (Box 810)
        - Education/Special Incentive Grants 1979 (Box 810)
        - Emergency Loan Program 1980 (Box 810)
        - Emergency Preparedness (Police) 1979-1980 (Box 810)
        - Employment and Training Issues 1981 (Box 810)
        - Employment/Unemployment Statistics 1979 (Box 810)
        - Energy
          - Conservation 1979 (Box 810)
          - Economics (Box 810)
          - Federal Funding to the State 1979-1980 (Box 810)
          - MERRA (Box 810)
          - President Carter's Plan 1979-1980 (Box 810)
        - Enterprise Zones 1980-1981 (Box 810)
        - Executive Office (Procedures Manual) 1979 (Box 810)
        - Export Policy 1979 (Box 810)
        - Export/Import Legislation 1980-1981 (Box 810)
        - Farmland 1979-1980 (Box 810)
        - Federal
          - Assistance Improvement Act 1981 (Box 810)
          - Budget 1979-1982, 5 folders (Box 810)
          - Council 1979 (Box 811)
          - Energy Related Funds to Michigan 1979 (Box 811)
          - Funds Distribution 1979-1981, 2 folders (Box 811)
          - Issues Book 1979-1982, 3 folders (Box 811)
          - Labor 1981 (Box 811)
          - Liaisons (Department) 1979, 3 folders (Box 811)
          - Medicaid 1981 (Box 811)
          - Policy Group (Box 811)
          - Priorities 1980 (Box 811)
          - Revenue Sharing 1978-1982, 4 folders (Box 811)
          - State Relations Unit 1979-1981 (Box 811)
          - Surplus land (Box 811)
          - Trade Commission 1979-1982, 2 folders (Box 811)
          - Unemployment Benefits 1980 (Box 811)
        - Flint Pension Pool Request 1981 (Box 811)
        - Gasoline Allocation/Shortages 1979-1980, 4 folders (Box 811)
        - General Motors 1980 (Box 811)
        - Genesee County
          - Evolution of Human Settlements 1979 (Box 811)
          - Metropolitan Alliance 1979 (Box 811)
        - Governor Rhodes' Self-Financing Program for America's Inner Cities 1980 (Box 811)
        - Governor Milliken
          - Meetings (w. Reagan, Weinberger, Baldridge) (Box 811)
          - Papers (Box 811)
        - Governors (US) Compensation (Box 811)
        - Great Lakes Maritime Academy 1979-1981 (Box 811)
        - Hamtramck 1979-1980, 3 folders (Box 811)
        - Harvard University (State/Local Government Program) 1979-1980 (Box 811)
        - Hazardous Wastes 1979-1980, 3 folders (Box 811)
        - Headlee Tax Proposal 1979 (Box 811)
        - Health 1978-1980, 2 folders (Box 811)
        - Highland Park 1981 (Box 811)
        - Hispanics 1979 (Box 811)
        - Housing
          - Cooperative housing (labor) (Box 811)
          - HUD (701 participation grant) (Box 811)
          - MSHDA 1979-1981, 4 folders (Box 811)
        - Human Resources Agency Group 1979 (Box 811)
        - Indians
          - Definition of 1978-1980 (Box 811)
          - Fishing Rights 1979-1981 (Box 811)
        - Industrial Revenue bonds 1981 (Box 811)
        - Inflation 1979 (Box 811)
        - Intergovernmental Relations 1979-1980 (Box 811)
        - Japan/US Trade 1980 (Box 811)
        - Jobs for America's Graduates 1982 (Box 811)
        - Kinchloe AFB (Conversion to Civilian Use) (Box 812)
        - Lapeer Sewage Treatment plant 1979 (Box 812)
        - Large Lakes Research Station 1981 (Box 812)
        - Local County Audits 1979-1980 (Box 812)
        - Local Government
          - Investment Pool 1980 (Box 812)
          - Recodification 1979 (Box 812)
          - Report of Governor's Special Commission (Box 812)
        - Lousma, Colonel 1982 (Box 812)
        - Macomb County Sewer Problem 1978-1980 (Box 812)
        - Management and Budget (Box 812)
        - Mass Transit 1979 (Box 812)
        - Maybank Amendment 1981 (Box 812)
        - Mental Health and the Economy 1980 (Box 812)
        - Mental Health Systems Act 1980-1981 (Box 812)
        - Michigan Associations
          - Counties (Box 812)
          - Regions (Box 812)
          - Townships (Box 812)
        - Michigan Efficiency Task Force 1978 (Box 812)
        - Michigan International Partners 1977-1979 (Box 812)
        - Michigan Meat Inspection Program 1979-1980 (Box 812)
        - Michigan Qualified Bond Program 1978-1979 (Box 812)
        - Michigan in the Space Program (Box 812)
        - Michigan Volunteer Winterization 1979-1980 (Box 812)
        - Minority Procurement 1979 (Box 812)
        - National Bank Development Act 1979 (Box 812)
        - National Commission for Employment 1982 (Box 812)
        - National Consumer Cooperative Bank 1979 (Box 812)
        - National Main Street Program 1980 (Box 812)
        - National Public Policy Issue (Box 812)
        - Natural Gas 1977 (Box 812)
        - Neighborhood Assistance Act 1979 (Box 812)
        - Neighborhood Office Proposal 1979 (Box 812)
        - New Detroit 1979-1980 (Box 812)
        - Northeast-Midwest Coalition 1979-1980 (Box 812)
        - Nuclear Power 1979 (Box 812)
        - Olivet, Michigan 1980 (Box 812)
        - Older Americans Act 1979 (Box 812)
        - Olympic Committee Fund Raising 1980 (Box 812)
        - One-Day Layoff Plan 1982 (Box 812)
        - Ontonagon County Economic Development 1979 (Box 812)
        - Orion Twp. (Pontiac Motors) 1980 (Box 812)
        - Paperwork Reduction (Box 812)
        - Partnership for Prosperity Fund 1982 (Box 812)
        - Personal Health Services-314 1979-1981 (Box 812)
        - Pontiac Silverdome Study 1980-1981 (Box 812)
        - Population Projections 1979-1980 (Box 812)
        - Presidential Elections
          (See Boxes 1437-1438)
          - Candidates 1980, 4 folders (Box 813)
          - Issues 1980, 4 folders (Box 813)
        - Presidential Interns Program 1980 (Box 813)
        - President's Council on Physical Fitness 1981 (Box 813)
        - Private Sector Initiatives Task Force 1982 (Box 813)
        - Public Health Services Act-314 1979 (Box 813)
        - Reagan's Budget/Federalism 1980-1982 (Box 813)
        - "Reagan's First Year" (Report) (Box 813)
        - Regional Primaries 1982 (Box 813)
        - Regionalism and Government Functions 1979 (Box 813)
        - Reorganization of Departments 1980 (Box 813)
        - Republican National Committee 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 813)
        - Republican National Convention 1979-1980 (Box 813)
        - Republican Platform 1980 (Box 813)
        - Republican Policy Committee 1979-1980 (Box 813)
        - Revenue Sharing 1979-1981, 4 folders (Box 813)
        - Riegle Economic Initiative 1981 (Box 813)
        - River Island Area Plan 1980 (Box 813)
        - Rockefeller Public Service Awards 1980 (Box 813)
        - Royal Oak Township 1978-1979 (Box 813)
        - Rural
          - Banking 1979 (Box 813)
          - Elderly Housing 1979 (Box 813)
        - Saginaw County Metropolitan Planning 1979 (Box 813)
        - St. Joseph Twp. 1979 (Box 813)
        - 70001 Proposal-Training Young Offenders 1979 (Box 813)
        - Small Business 1977-1980 (Box 813)
        - Small/Rural Community Development 1978-1980 (Box 813)
        - SEMCOG 1979-1981 (Box 813)
        - Southwest Detroit Development Association 1979-1980 (Box 813)
        - Spanish-speaking Commission (Box 813)
        - State-Federal Rural Development 1980 (Box 813)
        - State General Revenue Sharing 1979 (Box 813)
        - State Projects 1978-1980, 3 folders (Box 813)
        - State of the State 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 813)
        - Subdivision Control Act 1979-1980 (Box 813)
        - Substance Abuse Services (Box 813)
        - Supersewer 1979 (Box 813)
        - Synfuels Program 1979 (Box 813)
        - Taxes 1979-1980, 3 folders (Box 813)
        - Title V Regional Commissions 1979 (Box 813)
        - Trade Barriers/Adjustments 1980, 2 folders (Box 813)
        - Transition: Federal-State Issues (Box 813)
        - Transportation (CITE) 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 813)
        - Undocumented Workers 1977-1980 (Box 814)
        - Unemployment
          - Compensation 1977-1979 (Box 814)
          - Insurance 1979-1982, 2 folders (Box 814)
        - UP Office (Mary Soper) 1979-1980 (Box 814)
        - Urban Affairs 1978-1980, 8 folders (Box 814)
        - USS Nautilus 1980 (Box 814)
        - Veterans Facilities (Box 814)
        - Washington Office 1979-1982, 5 folders (Box 814)
        - Water Resources 1982, 2 folders (Box 814)
        - Water Use Fees Issues 1981 (Box 814)
        - Wayne County 1979-1980 (Box 814)
        - Welfare Reform 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 814)
        - White House Fellowships 1981, 2 folders (Box 814)
        - Winter Navigation 1979, 4 folders (Box 814)
        - Women and Work Project 1980 (Box 814)
        - Women's Issues 1979 (Box 814)
        - Workers' Compensation 1980, 3 folders (Box 814)
        - Young Americans Medal Committee 1981 (Box 814)
        - Youth Employment 1980, 2 folders (Box 814)
    - Kathy Stariha 1974-1978
      - PBB
        - Agriculture, Department of
          - Topical Files
            - Inspection and Slaughterhouses (Box 815)
            - Quarantine (Box 815)
            - USDA/Purdue University (Box 815)
            - Milk/Fat Comparisons (Box 815)
            - Three Phase Herd Health Survey (Box 815)
            - Cost Estimates 1976 (Box 815)
            - Suppression of Information 1977 (Box 815)
            - Feed and Elevator Testing (Box 815)
            - Consumer Attitude Survey (Box 815)
          - Hearings
            - May 29, 1975 (Box 815)
            - June 10, 1976, 4 folders (Box 815)
        - Canada
          - Federal Beef Export (Box 815)
          - I. Ross Reid Visit (Box 815)
          - Michigan Food Import Legislation (Box 815)
        - Demonstration 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 815)
        - Disposal Problems
          - Animal Disposal, 3 folders (Box 815)
          - Gratiot County Landfill (Box 815)
          - Pyrolysis (Box 815)
          - Cesium Degradation (Box 815)
          - Public and Private Landfills (Box 815)
        - Executive Office
          - Action Plan (5 step) May 1976 (Box 816)
          - Special Message June 1976 (Box 816)
          - Press Releases (Box 816)
          - Internal Memoranda 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 816)
          - Meeting with Farmers March 1976 (Box 816)
          - FDA/Department of Agriculture 1977 (Box 816)
          - Re-evaluation of Position 1977 (Box 816)
          - Expenses related to PBB (Box 816)
        - Financial Assistance
          - HB 5033 (veto) (Box 816)
          - Agricultural Loan Authority (Box 816)
          - Pool Settlement December 1975 (Box 816)
          - FHA Loans (Box 816)
          - Available Public Assistance (Box 816)
          - Insurance Settlement Pools (Box 816)
          - Oversight Committee 1976 (Box 816)
          - Toxic Chemical Contamination Relief Act (Box 816)
          - Griffin/Riegle Package (Box 816)
          - Toxic Substance Loans, 2 folders (Box 816)
          - Michigan Legal Services Survey (Box 816)
          - Income Tax problems (Box 816)
        - Health Studies
          - Short-term Study (Box 816)
          - Long-term Study 1975-1978, 4 folders (Box 816)
          - Selikoff Studies 1976, 2 folders (Box 816)
          - Baar/Weil Children's Study (Box 817)
          - Lymphocyte Study (Box 817)
          - NIOSH Study of Michigan Chemical Company (Box 817)
          - Ford/UM Hospitalizations (Box 817)
          - Chanda Dermatology Study (Box 817)
          - General Population Study, 4 folders (Box 817)
          - Michigan Chemical Company Workers (Box 817)
          - MSU/E. Seagull Study of Developmental Abilities of Exposed Children (Box 817)
          - Toxic Substances in Food Chains (Box 817)
        - Interest Groups (alphabetically)
          - A-G, 23 folders (Box 817)
          - H-Z, 32 folders (Box 818)
        - Legal Actions
          - Tacoma v. Michigan Chemical Company (Box 818)
          - Grand Jury Indictment (Velsicol) 1977 (Box 818)
          - Farm Bureau Services Animal Division (Box 818)
          - Brady Indictments (Box 818)
          - Petitions for Orders of Superintending Control October 1977 (Box 818)
          - Health Damage Lawsuit 1977 (Box 818)
          - Statute of Limitations (Box 818)
          - Grand Jury Investigations 1976 (Box 818)
          - Executive Powers of the Governor (Box 818)
          - Michigan v. Michigan Chemical Company (Box 818)
          - Actions against Michigan Department of Public Health (Box 818)
          - Judge William Peterson's Ruling (Box 818)
        - Legislative Investigations
          - Welborn Committee (Box 818)
          - Albosta Committee (Box 818)
          - Wilson Committee (Box 818)
          - Senate Appropriations Hearings (Box 818)
        - Legislative Proposals
          - Labeling Proposal (Albosta) (Box 818)
          - Condemnation/Disposal (Ostling) (Box 818)
          - Commercial Feed Guidelines (Albosta) (Box 818)
          - Food Law Amendment (Albosta) (Box 818)
          - Wilson Committee (Box 818)
        - Media
          - Washington Post (Box 818)
          - Bill Bonds' Transcript October 1977 (Box 818)
          - Fetzer Documentary 1977 (Box 818)
          - Thames Television-This Week (Box 818)
          - Larson/Stariha Proposal (Box 818)
          - Media Relations Committee (Box 818)
          - ABC Interview, Spring 1977 (Box 818)
          - NBC Story February 1978 (Box 818)
          - Poisoning of Michigan (Part II) 1978 (Box 818)
        - Michigan State University
          - Diagnostic Clinic (Box 819)
          - Eddington Herd (Box 819)
          - Hillman Iodine Study (Box 819)
          - Soil Absorption Studies (Box 819)
          - Information Series (Box 819)
          - Workshop on PBB October 1977 (Box 819)
          - Food Contamination Problems (Box 819)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 819)
        - Natural Resources
          - Wildlife Testing (Box 819)
          - Saginaw Bay Problem (Box 819)
          - DNR Water Testing (Box 819)
        - Public Act 77
          - General Implementation (Box 819)
          - Action Reports (Box 819)
          - Animal and Milk Disposal (Box 819)
          - Exemptions (HCR 436) (Box 819)
          - General Amendments (HB 5811 and HCR 498) (Box 819)
          - Indemnity Payments (Box 819)
          - Holding Payments (SCR 250-Allen) (Box 819)
          - Spaniola's Bill (HB 4109) (Box 819)
          - Farm Bureau/USDA/FDA Meeting February 1977 (Box 819)
          - Porter Approach (Box 819)
          - Diehl Proposal (Box 819)
          - Agriculture Promotion Campaign (Box 819)
          - Public Health Implementation (Box 819)
          - Budget (Box 819)
          - Daily Testing Summaries, 2 folders (Box 819)
          - Recontamination (Box 819)
          - Hertel Amendments (SB 1605) (Box 819)
          - Program Costs Estimates February-November 1977 (Box 819)
          - Public Act 77 as Amended (Box 819)
          - Toxic Substance Control (HB 4804 SB 1495) (Box 819)
        - Public Health, Department of
          - General Information (Box 820)
          - Breast Milk Study, 2 folders (Box 820)
          - PCB Study (Box 820)
          - Communications Consultant (Box 820)
          - Notes from Daily Briefings (Box 820)
          - Consumer Attitude Survey (Box 820)
          - Advisory Committee (Box 820)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 820)
        - Responsible Parties
          - Michigan Chemical Company/Velsicol (Box 820)
          - Farm Bureau Services, 2 folders (Box 820)
        - Scientific Advisory Panel
          - General (Box 820)
          - Response to Milliken's Request for data (Box 820)
          - Panel's Curriculum Vitae (Box 820)
          - Report May 1976 (Box 820)
          - Expenses (Box 820)
          - Letter Receipt Log (Box 820)
          - Compilation of Responses (Box 820)
        - United States Congressional Investigations
          - Riegle Hearings 1977, 3 folders (Box 821)
          - Moss Investigation (Box 821)
        - United States Government Agencies
          - General Accounting Office Report (Box 821)
          - Department of HEW Subcommittee, 2 folders (Box 821)
          - Environmental Protection Agency
            - Workgroup (Box 821)
            - PBB in Other States (Box 821)
          - Food and Drug Administration
            - Ex-Lax Contamination (Box 821)
            - Canine Studies (Box 821)
            - Special Assistance Appointment (Box 821)
            - USDA Animal Health Study (Box 821)
          - Miscellaneous
            - General 1978, 2 folders (Box 821)
            - Early Correspondence, 1974-75, 2 folders (Box 821)
            - Robo and White Paper 1976 (Box 821)
            - Robo and Sample Letter, 1977-78 (Box 822)
            - Chronology, 2 folders (Box 822)
            - Summary of Press Contracts September 1977 (Box 822)
            - Sample Letters 1976 (Box 822)
            - Bibliography (Box 822)
            - Contaminants in Firemaster (Box 822)
    - Manfred Tatzmann 1979-1980
      - Office of Recipient Rights: Administrative
        - Community Mental Health Guidelines (Box 822)
        - Institutional Blank Forms (Box 822)
        - Meetings (Box 822)
        - Newsletters (Box 822)
        - Policies and Reference Material (Box 822)
        - Rights Advisors/Officers (Box 822)
        - Staffing (Box 822)
        - Statistical Summaries, Monthly (Box 822)
      - Office of Recipient Rights: Recipient Rights Study
        - Bocskay, Jan, 2 folders (Box 822)
        - Budget Information (Box 822)
        - Civil Rights, Department of (Correspondence) (Box 822)
        - Corrections, Department of, 3 folders (Box 822)
        - Distribution Lists (Box 822)
        - Education, Department of (Correspondence) (Box 822)
        - Labor, Department of (Correspondence) (Box 822)
        - Long, Bill, 2 folders (Box 822)
        - Management and Budget, Department, 2 folders (Box 822)
        - Mental Health, Department of (Correspondence) (Box 822)
        - Protective Services Work Group, 2 folders (Box 822)
        - Public Health, Department of, 2 folders (Box 822)
        - Recommendations of Study (Box 822)
        - Request for Proposal, 2 folders (Box 822)
        - Research Group Contract, 2 folders (Box 822)
        - Rights Protection Requirements Comparison (Box 822)
        - Social Services, Department of, 2 folders (Box 822)
      - Office of Recipient Rights: Correspondence (Re: Institutions)
        - Alpine Center (Box 822)
        - Caro Regional Mental Health Center (Box 822)
        - Clinton Valley Center (Box 822)